JOSE CARLOS ROMÁN RUBIO

Software engineer

Website: https://josecarlosroman.com

BACKGROUND

2014

Ingeniería técnica en Informática de Sistemas (3-year university degree focused on Computer Engineering, Information Technology and Software Engineering). Final grade: NOTABLE. FYP defended on 13th of March and marked as SOBRESALIENTE. University of Málaga.

SKILLS

Computer science

Total experience in years (Experience in years on projects to individuals, institutions and companies)

< Less than a year of experience > More than 10 years of experience

Microsoft		Oracle & Java		Google	
C#	6 (5)	Java	4 (0)	Android development	2 (<)
TypeScript	2 (0)	Java GUI (Swing, applets)	1 (0)	Firebase	1 (0)
Desktop (Windows Forms)	4 (3)	Java EE (servlets, JSP)	1 (0)	Git	3 (0)
Desktop (WPF)	3 (2)	MySQL	6 (4)	Material Design	1 (0)
ASP.NET	2 (1)	Spring MVC	< (0)		
ASP.NET MVC	1 (0)	Apache		Apple	
SOAP Web services (asmx)	4 (3)	HTTP server	4 (3)	iOS development	< (0)
SOAP Web services (WCF)	1 (1)	Cordova	1 (0)	Objective C	< (0)
REST Web services (Web API)	1 (0)	Struts	< (0)	Swift	< (0)
Reporting Services (SSRS)	1 (0)	Subversion	1 (1)		
Analysis Services (SSAS)	1 (1)	Tomcat	1 (1)		

Web		JavaScript		PHP	
HTTP	> (4)	JavaScript (ES5-ES6)	> (4)	PHP	> (3)
REST API	4 (1)	Node.js, NPM	3 (0)	Laravel	1 (0)
HTML (5)	> (4)	Express	1 (0)	Symfony 2/3	< (0)
CSS	> (4)	Angular	2 (0)	WordPress	2 (2)
SASS	2 (0)	React	< (0)	Prestashop	1 (<)
Bootstrap (3-4)	3 (1)	Vue	< (0)	Joomla!	< (<)
Foundation	< (0)	Ionic Framework	1 (0)	Drupal	< (0)
SEO	1 (1)	JS Library (jQuery)	> (4)		
		JS Library (rxJS)	1 (0)		
		JS Tools (Grunt, gulp)	2 (0)		
		JS Tools (Webpack)	1 (0)		

Software development		Databases		Other	
Computer programming	> (7)	SQL	> (6)	Computer architecture	2 (<)
C/C++	1 (0)	Relational databases	> (6)	Operating systems	> (1)
Python	< (0)	MongoDB	1 (0)	Linux	1 (<)
l		ORM (eloquent)	1 (0)	Computer Networks	> (0)
I		ORM (doctrine, EF, hibernate)	< (0)		
		ODM (mongoose)	1 (0)		

Languages

Upper-intermediate in written English.

Personal skills

- Organized, critical thinking, good at solving problems, efficient, self-motivated

PROJECTS

2016/01 – 2016/09 Healthcare desktop application. Skills: .NET, WPF, MySQL, Business Intelligence
2012/10 – 2015/03 Sports training software. Skills: .NET, winForms, web services, SQL Server.

GitHub: https://github.com/jcdotnet

EXPERIENCE

2016/01 – present	Software engineer. Self-employed
2014/09 – 2014/11	Programmer at Grupo JyA.
2014/06 – 2014/09	.NET and PHP Programmer at BOLT accelerator.
2008/06 - 2010/01	Owner and manager of a fashion and accessories shop.

COURSES AND CERTIFICATES

2017	Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: Angular. <u>Verified certificate and grade.</u>
2017	Front-End UI Frameworks and tools: Bootstrap 4. Verified certificate and grade.
2017	UDEMY: https://www.udemy.com/user/josecarlosromanrubio/
2016	Server-side development with nodeJS. <u>Verified certificate and grade.</u>
2016	Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: AngularJS. <u>Verified certificate and grade.</u>
2016	MongoDB using the MEAN stack. MongoDB. Self-paced. Grade achieved: 100%.
2015	Web Application Development with JavaScript and MongoDB. University of London. Length: 4 weeks. Grade achieved: 100%
2015	Intro to meteor.js development. University of London. Duración: 4 semanas. Calificación: 92%.
2015	Interactive programming in Python. Rice university. Length: 8 weeks. Grade achieved: 100%
2015	HTML5.2x: Advanced techniques. W3C. Length: 4 weeks. Grade achieved: 86%
2015	Game programming with C#. UCCS. Length: 12 weeks. Grade achieved: 100%
2015	CS188.1x: Artificial Intelligence. UC Berkeley. Length: 12 weeks. Grade achieved: 84%.
2015	Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems. University of Maryland. Length: 8 weeks. Grade achieved: 94.8%.
2012	English B1 certificate. EOI Málaga
2007	Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (.NET framework 2.0). Forman. Length: 670 hours.
2006	Desarrollo de aplicaciones J2EE with work experience in Novasoft. Forman. Length: 360 hours.